You know, in this war that happened in
May, India for the first time escalated
it to a level where we had cruise
missiles flying into
Pakistan with direct hits at the time.
And from the Indian side, this constant
line is
is said from right at from the prime
minister level up.
He says that
that we called their nuclear bluff.
You said that you were told unofficially
that you knew that America knew where
the nukes were. Do you think Americans
told India that the control of Pakistani
nukes also lies with America?
I doubt it.
I doubt it because of the vociferousness
with which
the Pakistanis have come out publicly
and said that they control the nukes.
But I can tell you definitively
that
the State Department was telling both
sides, "If you're going to fight, fight.
Keep it short and keep it non-nuclear."
If nuclear weapons are introduced, the
whole world is going to change. And so I
think there was restraint on both sides.
The Pakistanis need to come to a policy
conclusion that there's nothing positive
for them in fighting India. Nothing.
Literally nothing good will come of a of
an actual war between India and Pakistan
because the Pakistanis will lose. Mhm.
It's as simple as that. They'll lose.
And I'm not talking about nuclear
weapons. I'm talking just about a
conventional war. The Pakistanis will
lose.
Right. And so there's no benefit to
constantly provoking the Indians. Right.
Last question on the nuclear issue. I
promise I'll move on after that.
Okay, let's nix the control part. You
you doubt that the actual control, but
there was a New York Times article
written by the by the New York Times
editor that time for the national
security that uh that President Bush had
folded in hundreds of millions of
dollars in grants
uh to Pakistan to safeguard their
nuclear assets. The New York Times knew
about this program, but decided to sit
on it for a number of months before they
finally published it. So even if they
don't control it, did they give
technology to safeguard it?
Most likely, yes.
What would that technology be?
That I don't know. I I It's not my area
of expertise, and I couldn't speculate.
But I will tell you that
the fact that the New York Times sat on
the article
is a way of confirming its truth. And
what I mean is
when one of the big outlets, the New
York Times, the Washington Post, the
Wall Street Journal,
you know, the Los Angeles Times or one
of the big broadcast news networks,
um when they
come across information like this that's
really it's big and it involves
classified information,
they always ask the White House to
confirm or to deny.
If the information is truly classified
and it's sensitive,
the national security advisor will ask
for a meeting. Sometimes the meeting is
with the president and the head of the
newspaper. Usually it's the national
security advisor.
And they'll say, "Look,
yes, it's true, but it's so sensitive
that if you publish it, it will put
lives in danger."
Almost always, they'll sit on the
article
until enough time passes
that people aren't in danger anymore.
The fact that they sat on the article is
confirmation that it was true. Mhm.
[Music]